netrk.net 2019-03-24

# Privacy Policy - netzeffekt

Thank you for your interest in our website and in our company, “Netzeffekt GmbH” (“we”, “us”). We are highly committed to protecting your personal data and to respecting your privacy. In order to keep you informed about the scope of the collection and the use of your personal data when visiting our website, [www.netzeffekt.de](https://www.netzeffekt.de/) (“website”), please take note of the following information:

### 1\. Controller

The data controller for the processing of your data in respect of our website is:

Netzeffekt GmbH, Theresienhöhe 28, 80339 München  
Telephone: +49 (0) 89 4161464 0  
E-Mail: [datenschutz@netzeffekt.de](mailto:datenschutz@netzeffekt.de)

You can contact our Data Protection Officer by sending an email to:  
E-Mail: [datenschutz@netzeffekt.de](mailto:datenschutz@netzeffekt.de)

### 2\. Anonymous data collection

In general, you can visit our website without telling us who you are. We neither collect the name of your internet service provider nor do we keep track of the website you are coming from or the name of the requested file.

### 3\. Processing personal data

We do not collect any personal data on our website unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy.

When accessing our website, we collect and retain the IP address assigned to your computer in order to transmit the requested content of our website to your computer (i.e. texts, images, games and product information as well files that are available for download, etc.). In this context the legal basis is Art. 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). In addition, we process data in order to detect and prosecute misuse. In this regard, the legal basis is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests in the processing of data are to ensure the proper functioning of our website, as well as the transactions carried out thereon.

In addition, we collect and process information about the use of our website, such as the type of browser used, as well as the date and time of the website uses. We also process such data to optimize our website and offers, as well as for market analysis. The legal basis is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests in processing such data are based on being able to offer you a needs-orientated and optimized website according to the devices used. You are not obliged to provide us with your data. However, without your data we won´t be able to perform the mentioned services.

If you contact us via email or one of our contact forms (except for applications, here clause 4 of this Privacy Policy applies), the data transmitted will be stored in our system solely for the purpose of individual communication with you. For this purpose the legal basis is Art. 6 (1)(b) GDPR (if the communication is required for the performance of a contract with you or in order to take steps prior to entering a contract) or our legitimate interests in communicating with you at your request, Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Please note that the transfer of data is not encrypted and therefore no confidential information should be sent via email. In case you have given consent to the processing of personal data according to Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR, you can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us by email at [datenschutz@netzeffekt.de](mailto:datenschutz@netzeffekt.de), without affecting the lawfulness of processing prior to the withdrawal of consent. You are not obliged to provide us with your data. However, without your data we won´t be able to process your request.

### 4\. Applicant data

You can either apply to us by mail or email or via our contact form on our website at <https://www.netzeffekt.de/karriere>. In that case, we only process your data solely for the purpose of the application process. The legal basis is Sec. 26(1) of the new Federal Data Protection Act (“Bundesdatenschutzgesetz/BDSG-neu”).

The recipients of the data are exclusively the persons involved in the application process.  
If your application is rejected, the retention period is six months beyond the completion of the application process. This retention period is based on any possible assertion of claims in accordance with the General Act on Equal Treatment (“Allgemeines Gleichbehand-lungsgesetz”/”AGG”).

With your consent we may agree to a different retention period. Consequently, the legal basis is consent, Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR.

You are not obliged to provide us with your application data. However, without your data we won´t be able to process your application.

### 5\. Cookies

Among other things, our website uses so-called “cookies”, which serve to make our web presence more user-friendly, more effective and more secure – for example, when it comes to speeding up navigation on our platform. In addition, cookies enable us to measure the frequency of website views and general navigation. Legal basis is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests in the use of cookies consist of the aforementioned purposes of improving our internet presence. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer system. Please note that some of these cookies are transferred from our server to your computer system, which are mostly so-called “session cookies”. “Session cookies” are characterized by the fact that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive after the end of the browser session. We only use those cookies to conduct/provide the services requested by the user. The legal basis is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests in processing data in such a way are to optimize website settings for the device you use and to customize the user interface. Other cookies remain on your computer system and allow us to recognize your computer system next time you visit (so-called “persistent cookies”). Of course you can refuse cookies at any time if your browser allows you to do so.

### 6\. Use of Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators and to provide other services related to website activity and internet use. Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required by law or as far as third parties process this data on behalf of Google. In no case, will Google link your IP address with other Google data.

You can prevent the installation of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; however, we point out that in such case you may not be able to use all the functions of the website to its full extent. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You can object to the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future. Our contact information for the objecting can be found on our copyright page. Alternatively, you can use the Google Analytics opt-out add-on (<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>), if it is available for your browser.

Please note that this website uses Google Analytics with an IP anonymization extension and therefore IP addresses are only further processed in an abbreviated form in order to avoid direct references to individuals.

The use of Google Analytics is based on our legitimate interests in a needs-based design, the statistical evaluation and efficient promotion of our website and the fact that they are not overridden by your legitimate interest. The legal basis is Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR. You are not obliged to provide us with your data. However, without your data we won´t be able to provide the aforementioned services.

### 7\. Your rights regarding the processing of personal data

Upon request, we will provide you with access to your personal data at any time. You are also granted the following rights if the legal requirements are met:

  * Right to rectification of your personal data in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR where they are inaccurate.
  * Right to erasure (“Right to be forgotten”) of your personal data without undue delay where certain grounds apply in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR. This may be the case if your personal data are no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed, as well as in case of unlawful processing, of an objection or for compliance with a legal obligation to erase.
  * Right to obtain restriction of processing if certain grounds are met in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR. In particular you have this right when the accuracy of your personal data is contested between the user and us; for the period that is required to verify the accuracy of the data as well as where the user opposes the erasure of his or her personal data and requests the restriction of the use of his or her personal data instead. Further, in the event that the data is no longer needed for our intended purposes, but they are required by the user for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, as well as where the successful exercise of the right to object is still contested between us and the user.
  * **Right to object to processing of your personal data in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR that is, inter alia, based on Art. 6 (1)(e) or (f) GDPR. We will no longer process personal data, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or your establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.**
  * Right to data portability according to Art. 20 GDPR: you have the right to receive the personal data with which you have provided us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you have the right to transmit that information to another controller, i.e. another service provider. The prerequisite for this is that the processing is based on consent or a con-tract or the processing is carried out by automated means.

Should you wish to exercise your rights as described above, please contact us as controller of the website as follows:

Netzeffekt GmbH  
Theresienhöhe 28  
80339 München  
E-Mail: [datenschutz@netzeffekt.de](mailto:datenschutz@netzeffekt.de)  
Telephone: +49 (0) 89 4161464 0

You can contact our Data Protection Officer as follows:  
E-Mail: [datenschutz@netzeffekt.de](mailto:datenschutz@netzeffekt.de)

### 8\. Other data use

Further processing or use of your personal data generally only takes place if permitted by applicable law or if you have consented to the processing or use of data.

Where there is further processing for a different purpose than the one for which the data was originally collected, we will inform you before carrying out this further processing for another purpose and we will provide you with further relevant information.

### 9\. Data erasure

In general, we delete or anonymize your personal data as soon as it is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which we collected or used them as set out in the preceding clauses, unless further storage of your personal data is required to comply with legal obligations.

### 10\. Automated decision-making or profiling

We don’t use automated processing for the purposes of decision-making or profiling.

### 11\. Automated decision-making or profiling

Should you think that the way we process your personal data is unlawful, you have the right to lodge a complaint with our competent supervisory authority, which you can contact as follows:

Bayerisches Landesamt für Datenschutzaufsicht  
Promenade 27 (Schloss)  
91522 Ansbach  
Telephone: +49 (0) 981 53 1300  
Telefax: +49 (0) 981 53 98 1300  
E-Mail: [poststelle@lda.bayern.de](mailto:poststelle@lda.bayern.de)

### 12\. Automated decision-making or profiling

The development of the internet and of our internet services may also have an impact on the processing of personal data. Therefore, we reserve the right to change this Policy in the future to comply with applicable data protection laws and, if necessary, to adjust it according to our modified data processing activities. Therefore, we recommend visiting our website from time to time in order to take note of any possible updates to our Privacy Policy.

Last updated: March 2018
